The design of this bottle
started in Terre Haute, Indiana
in 1915. At the time, Coca-Cola
was being sold at soda
fountains or in a glass bottle
called A Hutchinson. But this
simple straight sided bottle
was easy to copy and imitations
were flooding the market. The
solution, a national contest
for a new bottle that would
make Coca-Cola stand out. Even
if the bottle were broken or
you touch it in the dark. The
root glass company got to work
on their competition entry.
Looking up the word Coca in the
encyclopedia and coming across
an illustration for a cocoa
pod. The curvy ridge shape
appeal to the team who used it
as the basis for their winning
design. The first bottles hit
the shelves just a year later.
With the added touch of the
glass being coloured German
green. Later changed to Georgia
green. In honor of the Coca
Cola company's home state.
Sleek and iconic. This is the
design that's flaunted its
curves to become the trademark
of the most popular drink in
the world.