The design of this shoe starts
in Oregon in 1981 and with a
man called Tinker Hatfield. He
was an architect for Nike hired
to drop offices and showrooms
on the company's campus. After
making a statement on the
outside of the buildings, he
was asked to join the designers
on the inside. In a race to
develop sneakers, a former Nasa
engineer had recently
introduced the idea of sealing
air bubbles in the soles for
extra comfort and performance.
But competition was fierce and
Nike still needed an edge.
Hatfield headed to Paris in
search of inspiration. While he
was there, he visited the
Pompadu Center. A radical
building famous for its inside
out design which exposed the
building's components like
escalators and heating pipes
for everyone to see. Hatfield
decided to apply the same
principle to his own design.
Revealing the inner workings of
the shoe by making the air
cushioning system visible. The
team thought the air bubble
would seem like a weakness. But
the Nike Air Max one was an
instant hit when it launched in
19eighty-seven. Originally
pairs sold for $75. Now they go
for double that. Today Tinker
Hatfield is one of the most
successful shoe designers in
the world. He even created
those legendary self-lacing
sneakers a back to the future
fame. Stylish and innovative.
This is the design that stayed
one step ahead simply by being
turned inside out.