The design of the modern tennis
racket goes back to England in
eighteen seventy-four. And a
man named Major Walter Clofton
Wingfield. Wingfield patented
the rules for a game known as
lawn tennis. Standardizing
elements like balls, nets, and
rackets. For the next century,
rackets would be made of wood
and remain similar in shape to
Wingfield's original design.
But in 1961, French tennis
legend Renee Lacoste unveiled a
radical invention. The
crocodile as he was nicknamed,
had made a prototype using
metal. Just a few years Wilson
released the T2 thousand. The
first stainless steel racket
whose futuristic design caught
the eye of players like Billie
Jean King and Jimmy Connors.
It's small head and open throat
reduced air resistance and
helped Connors win the US Open
five times. The 1970s ushered
in an era of aluminum which was
lighter and easier to mold and
steel. This was followed by
fashionable oversized rackets
that had a larger sweet spot
and gave players more
Eventually, the quest for
lightness and durability led to
graphite rackets as well as
other materials like Kevlar and
graphene. Today, Wilson and
French brand Babylot dominate
both the men's and women's game
with the two brands winning 71%
of professional tournaments in
twenty seventeen. Precise and
powerful, this is the design
that's helped to create legends
with every stroke.