The design of this little
tree's car freshener goes way
back to 1952 in Watertown, New
York. And an unhappy milkman
who's complaining to one of his
customers about the bad smell
of spoiled milk. Lucky for him,
he was talking to Julius
Salmon, a Jewish chemist who'd
fled from Nazi Germany and
spent time living in the forest
of Canada studying the aroma of
alpine trees. After his chance
of counter with a milkman,
salmon started to create paper
soaked in natural pine oil. A
string was all attached to stop
people getting the perfume all
over their hands. The freshener
was originally in the shape of
a Bucksham pinup girl but
salmon changed its design to
the pine tree we know today.
This allowed the cellophane
wrapper to be rolled down
slowly so the fragrance would
last that little bit longer. As
the automotive industry took
off, so did little trees.
Filling the air with classics
like black ice, royal pine,
vanilla aroma, and of course
new car scent. Fragrant and
affordable, this is the design
that brings you the heady aroma
of a Canadian woodland. Whether
you're in a milk cart or taxi
cap.