The designing of this logo
began in Seattle in nineteen
seventy-one. With three
university friends who really
liked coffee. They also really
liked the Herman Melville novel
Loby Dick. So much so they
decided to name their company
after Captain Ahab's ship. But
branding exec Terry Heckler
decided P Quad Coffee didn't
sound quite right. So they went
with the name of the first
mate, Starbucks. Heckler then
trolled through maritime books
and found a 15th century
woodcut of a two-tailed siren.
In of luring sailors onto the
rocks, this mythical mermaid
would call people to come and
grab a cup of coffee.
Initially, her chest was bare
but after some complaints,
Peckler redrew the design with
long hair that covered her
body. The logo also went from
brown to green. A symbol of
freshness and growth. In 2011,
the Starbucks Siren was
redesigned with rounder
details. A longer shadow was
also introduced on the right
side of her nose. A small
element of asymmetry which made
her feel more human. She can be
spotted in 76 countries and
markets. Helping Starbucks to
reach a brand value of more
than eight point seven billion
dollars. Bold and alluring,
this is the design that started
with a myth and became a coffee
legend.