The design of this soy sauce
bottle goes back to 1945 in
Japan. A teenager named Kenji
Ekwan had witnessed the
aftermath of the atomic bomb
falling on his hometown
Hiroshima and was mourning the
loss of his sister and father.
After seeing the devastation,
Ekwan's path changed. He first
enrolled as a Buddhist monk
falling in the footsteps of his
father. But instead he decided
to become a creator of things
and bring happiness to people.
As a designer Aguan got a
contract to design a table top
soy sauce bottle for food
company Kikoman soy sauce is a
must for Japanese meals but it
was originally sold in big
bottles that were hard to hold
it took Aguan three years and
about 100 prototypes to
complete the design in 1961.
The result is a small glass
bottle with a narrow neck. A
shape reminiscent of
traditional Japanese sake
flasks. It allows you to see
how much sauce is left. It's
stable on surfaces and
comfortable to hold. The inward
angle of the tip of the spout
is also perfect at preventing
drips and controlling flow. The
design of the little soy sauce
bottle was just the start of
Equan's great journey. He also
went on to create other icons
of Japanese design. In Japan,
Ekwan has become almost as
recognizable as his bottle and
50 years later, still appeared
in commercials for the soy
sauce. Today, the bottle can be
found on the tables of homes
and restaurants in more than a
hundred countries and in two
thousand fifteen, the bottle
was even exhibited at the
Museum of Modern Art New York.
Simple but elegant. This is the
design made to create a small
moment of happiness without you
even knowing it.