The design of this board game
started nineteen oh four with a
woman named Elizabeth McGee.
She was a fan of a book called
Progress and Poverty by
economist Henry George. In it
he argued that renting out land
only profited a few individuals
at the expense of the
community. To teach people
about George's theories, Lizzie
McGee created a game with two
sets of rules. In one, players
all shared money when someone
purchased a piece of land and
in the other, everyone tried to
get as rich as possible while
bankrupting others. This way,
she hoped people would see how
unfair land grabbing was. The
landlord game as it was known
became popular particularly
among Quakers. With each person
drawing the board by hand onto
table cloths or fabric and
modifying the rules. One of
those people was Charles
Darrow. He would only use the
rules that were cutthroat and
made a version of the board in
the shape of his dining table.
He also took street names from
Atlantic City grouping them by
color and adding small
illustrations to create the
board we know today. When
Parker Brothers bought the
rights to Monopoly from Darrow
in 193five, they soon added a
Portly mascot with a top hat in
cane. Rumored to be modeled on
wealthy banker JP Morgan. They
also distributed every set with
metal tokens inspired by
trinkets Darrow had used for
his niece's charm bracelet.
Within a year of the release,
thirty-five, thousand copies of
Monopoly were being made each
week. Now more than one billion
people in 114 countries have
played the game. Classic and
familiar, this is the design
that set out to make us work
together but has been dividing
families ever since.