Picture New York City and
you're probably thinking about
Midtown, Times Square, the
Empire State Building, Grand
Central. This is Midtown
Manhattan. Tourists flock to it
while locals often try and fail
to avoid it. But there's more
to this part of town than
tourist traps and traffic
congestion. Midtown has been
electrified by a bolt of
Brooklyn Hip and Wall Street
money. Maybe it's time you took
a second look.
Midtown is everything between
14th street and Central Park
South. It's the world's largest
central business district. It
also has some of the most
expensive real estate and it
doesn't get any ritzier than
fifth Avenue which commands the
world's highest retail rents.
But if there's one building
more responsible than any other
for Midtown success, it's this
one.
Built in 1913, Grand Central
Terminal helped spark a boom in
construction that made Midtown
the centre of American
capitalism. This audacious
building is used by more than a
million people a week. A
century after it was built, it
has only now reached capacity.
That's future proofing.
New York embraces eating out.
There are over 45, 000
restaurants in the city. It
would take 125 years to eat in
everyone, not saying you
should. Here in Midtown the
restaurant scene is embracing
change. A number of Brooklyn
institutions have jumped the
river.
Roberta's Pizza started on the
other side of the East River in
2008 but their second outpost
is based in Urban Space Food
Hall SmackDab in Midtown.
You could be fooled into
thinking this is Williamsburg
not Park Ave.
Another Brooklyn import is
Ichiran, the Japanese ramen
chain whose first US restaurant
opened in Bushwick in twenty
sixteen. Here you can sit with
a group or in splendid
isolation in one of the
so-called flavor concentration
booths. Very serious. But if
you want to swap Brooklyn cool
for something a bit more
luxury, we've got the spot. The
office is an intimate speakeasy
offering pre-prohibition style
cocktails and a food menu to
match. You'll find it hidden
away on the 35th floor of the
super swanky Mandarin Oriental.
This is one of the most
expensive hotels in New York.
Rooms start at around $1, 000 a
night. But there are 113 other
hotels in Midtown offering
plenty of choices. So forget
the old wisdom that the
excitement is basically
anywhere but Midtown. This part
of Manhattan has something new
and exciting to offer whether
it's high end or rough and
ready.