This is the Chinese mega city
of Shenzhen. A gleaming
monument to China's economic
miracle. In 1980 it was a town
with around 60, thousand
residents. Now it's China's
technological hub with a
population of over 12 million.
Entrepreneurs, high-flying tech
graduates and international
companies flock here to join
the tech revolution. Welcome to
Shenzhen.
Shenzhen sits north of Hong
Kong in the Pearl River Delta.
One of the most densely
urbanised regions in the world.
The area has an estimated
population of one hundred and
20 million people. In 1980,
Shenzhen was dedicated a free
economic zone and experiment in
market capitalism in communist
China. The effects were
explosive. Shenzhen's
population skyrocketed in just
over 30 years.
The city has a massive migrant
workforce. Over 4 million
residents stay during the week
and then return home on the
weekend. But it's tech hardware
that's put this city on the
map. If Silicon Valley dreams
it up then this is where it's
made. This is Bay Market,
arguably the world's largest
electronics market. Filming
here is banned. Hi, hi, hi, hi,
hi. But here's a sneaky peek.
The market's neon lit corridors
stretch across multiple
buildings and many floors. The
stalls sell everything from the
latest gadgets to the tiniest
screws and many items are rip
offs. Chinese fakes of US
products. But if you wanted to,
you could buy all you need to
build your own smartphone or
100000 of them. Because
Shenzhen draws in workers from
across China, its food scene is
just as varied as its
population.
If you're looking for the full
banquet experience, Shane
Palace and the Shangrila Hotel
has got you covered. Their
dimsung lunch is a feast for
the eyes and the mouth. It's a
showcase of authentic cantonese
cuisine. Try something a little
more casual such as Chinese hot
pot. A simmering pot of soup
stock is kept on your table and
you put your choice of
ingredients in. One of the most
famous variations is flavoured
with citron pepper. So watch
out. It packs a serious spicy
punch. When you get the bill,
you'll notice QR codes. Here in
Shenzhen, they're used by
locals to pay for just about
everything. Simply scan the
code and the money is
transferred. Sounds great but
there's a hitch. You can't use
them unless you have a Chinese
bank account. So, a technology
to make life easier only works
if you're a local.
Finally, why not enjoy some
sport? Look at that. Shenzhen
style. Attacking the blue
engineer. This is Robomaster, a
competition put on by local
drone and tech company DJI.
Student teams from around the
world compete using a variety
of self-made robots to shoot
each other and destroy the
opposition base. Racer
ammunition as well. That's
right. The competition aims to
foster engineering and
programming and keep Shenzhen
at the forefront of the tech
revolution.