The Australia's Gold Coast is
situated in subtropical
Queensland just an hours drive
from the state capital Brisbane
it's a fast growing city of a
half a million people drawn by
the miles of perfect coastline
and a sun drenched lifestyle
The Central Gold Coast skyline
looks like a gathering of
giants wriggling their toes in
the warm Pacific. There's a
natural spirit here found in
the incredible beaches, the
ocean's shifting moods, and the
cool waterfalls and deep
forests of the Hinderland. But
there's a human spirit too.
Dedicated to family, vitality,
and having the time of your
life. The Gold Coast got it
start as a vacation retreat in
the 1850s near its northern
end. It's here that the Gold
Coast still shines brightest.
So Surfers Paradise is a
complete destination in itself.
A glittering resort, shopping,
and entertainment strip. Head
to the sky point observation
deck to see the Gold Coast
beaches unfurl in a twenty mile
ribbon of sand studded with
headlands, parks, and
waterways. Just to the south of
Surfers Paradise is Broad Beach
where the pace begins to slow.
The further you move down the
coast, the more relaxed the
vibe. Burleigh Heads is home to
a stunning national park and
one of Australia's legendary
surf breaks.
It's easy to see why this
headlamp has been an Aboriginal
gathering place for thousands
of years. A little further
south is Currumbin, a place
where the bush meets the beach.
Hit the waves between Elephant
and Currumbin rocks or just go
for a float in the sparkling
serenity of the estuary. Follow
the shoreline south to the Gold
Coast most southern beach side
neighborhood. Coolangatta. Just
a five minute drive from the
Gold Coast International
Airport. Coolangatta is the
region's gateway for most
international and interstate
visitors. With a parks,
sheltered beaches, and river,
Coolangatta is a popular choice
for families and when the
conditions arrive, it produces
some of the most spectacular
surf in Australia.
The Gold Coast offers plenty of
thrills besides its fabulous
coastline. It's the theme park
capital of Australia. Spend a
day riding the waves and water
slides at Wet and Wild. Just up
the road, cool off and ride the
tubes at Dream World's
Whitewater World. Dream World
is Australia's largest theme
park. It features over 40 rides
for all ages and themed lands
like Tiger Island,
Experience Hollywood on the
Gulf Coast at Warner Brothers
Movie World. Strap yourself in
and take off on some of the
best roller coasters down
under. Then buckle up for the
Hollywood Stunt Driver Show.
Next door at the Australian
Outback Spectacular, saddle up
to a three-course meal as some
of the country's best horsemen
and women celebrate the spirit
of the bush. At SeaWorld,
celebrate the spirit of the
ocean with some of the sea's
most endearing creatures and a
few of the less cuffly ones
too. There's also plenty of
rides to explore between the
shows.
If you're feeling the need to
settle the nerves after all
those theme parks, head for the
hills. Just a 30 minute drive
in land and perched high on the
rim of an ancient volcano is
Mount Tamborine. Explore the
rainforest trails and skywalk
before sampling the local
produce and wines at Tambourine
Village.
A little further south is
Springbrook, a world heritage
listed national park filled
with ancient forests, secret
places, and waterfalls that
have been flowing since the
dawn of time.
From up here, high on the
escarpment, the Gold Coast
beckons. Back to the sand, back
to the right, and back to the
spirit of Australia's favorite
beach destination.