Now is the time to visit
Spain's capital. After nearly a
decade of economic crisis,
Madrid is growing again. And
you can feel this confidence in
the central district of
Hosticia. Its streets team with
restaurants and boutique shops
supplying cakes, coffee and
cocktails to trendy locals and
visitors alike. Welcome to
Hosticia, Madrid.
Tucked just north of Madrid
city centre is Husticia. In
just a few years this area has
evolved into one of the city's
trendiest districts.
Spain is only recently
recovered from a long and
painful recession which gripped
the country from 2008 to 2014.
At its height, unemployment was
above 26% while youth
unemployment was above
55percent. Spain's economy is
now growing and the effect of
this hardship in Housticia has
not been the mass closure of
independent stores but instead
a flight to buy and support
local business. This is Do
Design, a store which captures
that spirit of creativity and
community. The shop
collaborates with emerging
artists and designers
constantly shifting its
collection. Here you'll find
fashion, interior and jewelry
brands you've never heard of
before. Surviving Spain's
recession has forced businesses
to think differently. This is
and the first thing you'll
notice is all the bottles of
liquor are their own
handwritten brands. During the
recession cocktails one thing
people cut down on. The owners
of Mathera had an idea. They
bought unbranded liquor and
infused it themselves making
every cocktails seven euros.
It's now one of Madrid's
coolest bars but some very
exciting flavours think rum
infused with cinnamon and
orange and gin with rosemary
and thyme.
One Spanish tradition that has
shown no signs of being under
threat despite recent trends is
churros deep fried sugar coated
snack is best enjoyed with a
hot chocolate just to top off
your sugar hit churros are
traditionally eaten for
breakfast this is Churia's
Santa Teresa one of the oldest
churros bars in the
neighbourhood it opens at 530
in the morning making it
popular with the post night
club crowd
If you're feeling guilty about
your churros hit, fitness guru
to the stars, Tracy Anderson,
has opened up her only
non-US-based studio here in
Madrid. The workouts are a
blend of dance, cardio, and
weights. The rooms are heated
and music is blasted at club
levels. Get ready to sweat.
Now, it's time for dinner and
you're spoilt for choice.
Hosticia is jam packed with
little hip restaurants. This is
Celso Imanolo run by two
brothers. It's charming and
intimate. It serves
contemporary Spanish food with
an expert eye for detail. The
speciality dish is based around
a huge tomato from northern
Spain. It's served with
avocado, mango, papaya, red
onion, olive oil, and fresh
herbs.
And finally, you can't come to
Madrid without seeing some
Flamenco. Touristy restaurant
come theaters monopolize the
Flamenco scene but you can be
more adventurous.
Casa Patas has been a focal
point of Madrid's Flamenco
scene since the mid-80s and
still attracts some of the best
artists from around the
country.