Miami, the name brings to mind
gorgeous beaches, warm weather,
and art deco landmarks. But at
the intersection of North and
South America, Miami has
exploded on to the
international cultural scene in
recent decades. Want to
experience the best of Miami?
Venture beyond Glitzy South
Beach and swing by these three
hot spots on the mainland. The
first stop is Coconut Grove.
Situated southwest of downtown
Miami, this upscale residential
enclave is one of Miami's
oldest and most iconic
neighborhoods. The gem of
Coconut Grove is Vizcaya Museum
and Gardens. Originally built
as a winter home by business
magnate James Deeren. The
Vizcaya Estate is nestled among
dense mangrove swamps and
offers a spectacular view of
Biscayne Bay. Your Nate Maine
House features a blend of
Italian renaissance revival and
broke architecture and inside
you'll find an exquisite
collection of art and
furnishings acquired by Deering
during his world travels. The
lush, expensive gardens
surrounding the main compound
are a welcome break from
Miami's hot sun and a prime
backdrop for your Instagram
feed. You. If you've built up
an appetite, head north and
you'll eventually reach
Southwest eighth Street better
known as Cale Ocho, the main
thoroughfare of Little Havana.
Even though Americans can now
fly to the real Havana in less
than an hour, Little Havana
remains an enthralling outpost
for the Cuban expatriot
community and a vibrant setting
for Cuban food, culture, and
ambiance. Drop by the walk-up
window at the legendary cafe
Versailles for a croquette or a
Cortarito, a supercharged Cuban
version of espresso. Day or
night you're bound to encounter
old friends catching up or a
heated debate about politics.
Right across the street is La
Carreta which serves a variety
of authentic Cuban specialties
including Ropa Vieja and rice
with sweet plantains. If you're
feeling lucky after lunch,
settle in for a street siding
of dominoes if you can find a
sea fittings. As evening
approaches, the energy and buzz
shifts to a bustling
art-infused area north of
downtown called Wynwood. No
other neighborhood in Miami has
undergone as dramatic a
transformation as this former
industrial district that has
been reborn as a hub for
international art galleries,
shops, and a diverse restaurant
scene. The year-round pleasant
weather and seemingly endless
collection of vibrant street
murals has made Wynwood into a
giant outdoor art gallery. For
a unique dinner option, drop by
1800 Lucky, an open food hall
in the style of an Asian
market. Featuring a collection
of vendors offering a variety
of dishes from fresh ramen to
steamed dim sum to hot baking
duck. Finish off the night with
matcha ice cream served in a
fish-shaped cone or an
Asian-inspired cocktail at the
bar. Looking around, it's hard
to believe that you're still in
Miami but when it's 80 degrees
in the middle of winter, you'll
be glad you are.