If you think of Macau, you
probably think about gambling
and for good reason. It's the
world's largest gambling hub.
The region generates four times
more gaming revenue than Las
Vegas. Making it one of the
richest places in the world.
But there's more to Macau than
slot machines and roulette
wheels. For over 400 years it
was a Portuguese colony.
Ancient Chinese temples sit on
streets paved with traditional
Portuguese tiles. Welcome to
car.
Macau is only a one hour ferry
ride from Hong Kong and is a
gambling Mecca. In 2 thousand
and 17, mainland Chinese
tourists made over 22 million
trips to Macau and spent $273
per person. There are 41
casinos in the region and the
gambling industry makes up 60%
of GDP. But there's more to
this city. You don't have to
spend your time throwing money
away in air conditioned rooms.
This is Macau Peninsula, a
large section of which is a
designated UNESCO world
heritage site. Here the blend
of Portuguese and Chinese
culture is plain to see.
Churches sit alongside temples
of fortresses bear a mix of
characteristics. These are the
ruins of Saint Paul's probably
the most well known landmark in
Macau. It was originally a 17th
century church and college but
was destroyed by fire in the
19th century. It features
baroque carvings of oriental
themes. The blend of cultures
has also shaped the food scene.
Street vendors will sell you
Portuguese custard tarts and
pork chop bun to Macau version
of a hamburger. At the other
end of the spectrum is Alocha.
This authentic Portuguese
restaurant keeps the colonial
culinary history of Macau
alive. Its interior design is a
nod to the area's naval
history.
Finally, check out the view
from the Macau Tower and then
leap off it. You can bungee
down from the platform 233
meters above the ground, sure
beats walking.