If you've traveled to Hong
Kong, chances are you've stayed
or worked here. Amongst the
skyscrapers of Hong Kong
Island. But Hong Kong Island is
running out of room to expand.
Housing is the least affordable
anywhere in the world and you
don't get much for your money.
The average size flat is
smaller than what you'd get in
Manhattan. And many Hong Kong
is live in apartments not much
bigger than a garage. It's
because of this pressure that
the next time you visit, you're
more likely to stay here.
Across Victoria Harbour in Siem
Satsoi.
Is not easy to say and it's
often mispronounced. So it's
known to expats as TST. Today
the area is a growing
metropolis packed with a huge
variety of restaurants, modern
hotels and sleek museums. So
it's hard to believe it once
looked like this. During the
1880s it was a watch post for
the British colony and some of
the grand old buildings still
remain. This is the eighty 81
Heritage Building which used to
be the headquarters of the
Marine Police. Now it's filled
with high end shopping, a
hotel, restaurants and bars but
most people come here to take
photos. Walk down the road a
couple of blocks and you'll
come to Hong Kong's iconic
Peninsula Hotel. Built in 1928,
it is made appearances in films
like James Bond and the Dark
Knight. It's known for its
fleet of Rolls Royce phantoms
painted in the hotels signature
green which it holds the record
for the largest single order.
Running through the centre of
TST is Nathan Road. What
started as a muddy country path
built by the British in 1861 is
now a shopper's paradise.
Nathan Road is probably best
known for its tailors and the
tradition of tempting or
twisting the arms of tourists
walking by. Handmade suits
start at around $300 but for
higher quality threads go to
Empire International tailors.
This unassuming store is in
fact the base of a global
operation. This family run
business sells suits around the
world mostly thanks to word of
mouth. Now you're dressed for
dinner, head to the top of one
peaking road tower. This gem of
a Chinese restaurant is made to
look like a Hong or old Chinese
alley. Go up two floors and
you'll find AquaSpirit, one of
Hong Kong's premium bars. It
has some of the best views of
the city. And when you get
tired of the hustle and bustle
of walk over to one of Hong
Kong's most famous institutions
the Star Ferry. Running since
1888, this is the oldest mode
of transportation across the
harbour and you can hop on for
just 30 cents and enjoy one of
the world's most photographed
harbours.