San Francisco looks and feels
like a big city but it's
actually quite small. It has a
population of under a million
and is only 47 square miles.
But what it lacks in size, it
makes up for in price San
Francisco is amongst America's
most expensive cities. The
soaring cost of living and the
injection of Silicon Valley
money has led some people to
claim that towns lost its soul
but have no fear there's still
plenty of mojo left by the bay.
Welcome to San Francisco.
San Francisco is the cultural,
commercial, and financial
center of Northern California.
This city's reputation is built
on its colourful history. It
hosted the beat generation and
the free love movement of the
60s and 70s and was the
birthplace of pride. But these
days the Bohemian dream is up
against it. The average rent
for a one bedroom apartment is
over $3, 000. Nearly four times
the US national average. So
when checking out the city
start by dodging the traffic
and embracing your inner flower
power by grabbing a bike.
Although San Francisco's fame
for its steep hills, many parts
of the city are actually
relatively flat.
Start your journey at Pier 39
and pay a visit to the seals.
These guys turned up after the
earthquake of 198nine and
they've stayed ever since.
A 10 minute ride away is
Chinatown. This is the oldest
and second largest Chinatown in
North America. And despite all
the city's rapid changes, it
remains unbowed. House of
Nanking is famous for its
delicious cuisine and direct
service that some people might
find a bit rude but don't take
it personally, it's all part of
the experience.
Another quick ride will get you
from Chinatown to south of
market or Soma. This vast
warehouse filled district is
home to countless live work
spaces. Red Door Coffee inside
the 111 Meena Art Gallery is
the perfect place to chill for
a moment before heading into
the heart of the mission. For
decades, the mission was a
middle-class immigrant enclave
but it was steadily gentrified
by hipsters starting in the
nineties. Here you'll find some
of the world's best burritos
served up mission style.
Taqueria El Castillo is one of
the best. Don't let their lack
of decor ward you off. This is
the real deal.
Now you're fueled up. It's time
to tackle the hills. Riding up
to the Golden Gate Park is
worth the effort. You'll pass
buffaloes, windmills, the
Academy of Arts and Science,
and the Flower Conservatory all
on your way to the Pacific. Now
kick your feet up in luxury at
Sutro's Curvehouse. Stylish
restaurant and lounge with
stunning panoramic views.
Perfect place to unwind and
watch the sunset.