London, it's easy to recognize.
But look closely at a map. In
the very centre, there's a one
square mile cutout. This is the
city of London which lives in a
city named London.
The city has its own mayor,
laws and police force. In fact,
it behaves more like a separate
country within the United
Kingdom. This is because the
cities been around for much
longer than the UK. It was
built by the Romans and has
remained semi autonomous ever
since. To embody its fiery
independence, the city's emblem
is a dragon, not a bad choice.
You'll spot these statues, they
guard the boundary of the
square mile.
Nowadays, the cities arguably
the financial capital of the
world. And London is the
world's biggest foreign
exchange market. But the city
has a tiny residential
population. Every weekday,
workers flood into the banks,
law firms, and offices which
fill the square mile.
But it's not all work. This is
1 PM. You might say no surprise
here city workers having a
drink but attitudes are
changing. The legendary long
lunch at the pub is now seen as
a bit of a macho relic. In 2017
Lloyds of London the legendary
insurance market told its
employees the party's over. No
more drinks during office
hours. But as you can see not
everyone got the memo. Because
here's the rub of it. The city
had a bit of a reputation. When
the after work crowd go home,
the place becomes a ghost town.
But that's changing and leading
the way are some high flying
dining spots. Sitting on top of
the Herron Tower is the Duck
and Waffle. It offers
twenty-four seven service with
a hell of a view. This is about
as refined as a twenty-four
hour waffle house gets. But the
most talked about new guest is
reinventing the city's
reputation is called the Ned.
Over 500 million pounds has
been spent turning this old
bank into a private members
club and hotel. With eight
restaurants in the lobby and a
bar that stays open till four
AM the Ned's injected some late
night atmosphere into the city.
This is after all the oldest
part of London and following an
injection of fun and flavor,
it's throwing down a challenge
to the rest of the city and
shaking off its stuffy
reputation.