Singapore is a truly
international city. There are
four official languages but
you'll hear dozens more on the
streets of this island city
state. Half the population is
temporary stopping in to work
or study for short stints and
that constant coming and going
creates a vibrant mix of
cultures.
Tucked under Malaysia,
Singapore was only founded in
nineteensixty-five. It's now
one of the richest nations in
the world and a global
financial hub.
Singapore invested a whopping 1
billion dollars in startups and
37, 000 international companies
are based here. The first thing
you need to know about
Singapore is it's not all work.
The city now claims six of the
world's best bars plus
forty-seven Michelin stars.
So let's start here at the
Swanky Atlas Bar. Front and
centre is the Colossal Gin
Tower packed with over 1000
varieties. This art deco bar
opened last year and was
quickly rated in the world's
top twenty. But if you're
looking for something a little
less shouty, then head over to
Deep Espoke.
The gins a style bar is
regularly rated one of the best
cocktail spots in the city.
It's sleek and sumptuous
interior draws in a sharply
dressed crowd. But you don't
have to spend a fortune to
enjoy the breadth of what
Singapore has to offer. The
city state has three major
ethnic groups. Chinese, Malay
and Indian. To have a taste of
the more traditional and
colourful side of Singapore.
Plan a day trip to the cultural
enclaves of Chinatown, Little
India or the Arab Quarter I But
if you want to eat where the
chefs choose to eat, try this.
Burntends is not a good option
for vegetarians. It specializes
in grilled meats and has become
a favorite of local and
visiting chefs. Set up by two
Australians, this modern
barbecue restaurant is famous
for its open kitchen and super
heated coal oven.
It's actually illegal to rent
out private homes in Singapore
so stick to hotels. This is the
Hyatt Anders Hotel one of many
luxury options. We have saved
what's probably Singapore's
most famous hotel and bar for
last and that's because you
can't get in there at the
moment. Raffles Hotel is where
the Singapore sling was
invented and it's reopening in
the fall of 2018 after a
massive reconstruction.
Finally, if you find yourself
with some downtime, go to see
the audacious gardens by the
bay. Populated with giant super
trees, these structures are
really huge hanging gardens.
The total cost of this public
park was $1 billion dollars.
Part of a push by Singapore to
transform into what they call a
city in a garden.