Nestled between rolling hills
Rwanda's capital is friendly
and welcoming confounding Creek
inceptions because twenty-four
years after the genocide which
shocked the world Kigali's
worked hard to reinvent itself
with its eyes on the future
with a host of startups a
burgeoning art scene great
dining and some of the world's
best coffee this African
capital is building a
reputation with tourists
welcome to Kigali
With a population of just over
1. 1 million people, Kigali is
both geographically and
culturally the centre of
Rwanda. Its streets are
spotlessly clean, crime is low
and the economy is growing.
Kigali is capturing tourists
who used to only pass through
on their way to safari or
gorilla tours. After the
shocking events of nineteen
ninety-four, the city and the
country wants to show the world
another side and create a new
legacy.
Gagali is trying to model its
economic growth of the likes of
Singapore and Seoul complete
with a city wide obsession with
keeping the streets clean.
Citizens are required once a
month to partake in a giant
neighbourhood cleaning effort.
On top of that it's illegal to
import, use or sell plastic
bags and it's taken very
seriously. Plastic bag
traffickers yeah that's a thing
have been fined and even
jailed. As a tourist you'll be
warned not to bring any into
the country when you arrive.
Staying in the city's easy with
over a hundred hotels including
the big names like the
Marriott, Radison Blue and the
Hilton. But arguably the best
known is the Hotel Demil
Colleen. It was here in 1994
that 1200 people took refuge
during the genocide. That story
inspired the film Hotel Rwanda.
Got trouble at the gate. At the
time it was the city's premium
spot. But these days newer
hotels offer more luxury.
Despite that sitting in the
lobby you can feel the charm is
here.
Internationally, Rwanda Coffee
is regarded as the best in East
Africa. But it's not popular
with the locals. Rwanda's are
more into tea. But despite this
Kigali has a handful of
excellent coffee shops. This is
Questioned Coffee where the
beans are sourced from female
farmers and roasted in house.
And this is Shokola Café a
trendy spot above Kigali's
public library. Here's a tip
when heading out. Dress up. The
locals look sharp and wandering
around in some old T-shirt and
shorts is not going to cut it.
When travelling around the
city, you'll notice bright
murals dotted around. This is
the work of a public art social
enterprise. In a city with
almost no graffiti. This is
public art supported by the
government. So it's more
positive messages than free
thinking street art anarchy but
the scene here is maturing.
There are a number of boutique
shops where you can pick up
some of the local arts and
crafts. This is Go Kigali
Boutique which also offers city
tours that will show you around
the town's most exciting bots.
Finally finish off your day
with a drink looking over the
city at the Hilton's new hotel
in the centre of town. With a
80 degree views and an
excellent cocktail menu watch
the sunset in style. Because
with so much excellent food,
drink and ease. Kigali could
well become a tourist must see
in the next few years. So get
in quick before the crowd
arrives.