Cambridge, could you imagine a
more idyllic university town?
With its narrow medieval
passageways and eight hundred
and 1 year old university, this
small English city is packed
with history. But Cambridge is
embracing the new, its
restaurant scene has moved on
from Pub Grub and has something
exciting yet still traditional
to offer. Welcome to Cambridge.
Cambridge is less than an hour
from London by train. Once
you've arrived, you're going to
want to do what the locals do
and get yourself a bike.
Cambridge is considered the
cycling capital of the UK.
They're everywhere. Bike hire
shops are peppered around and
parking is easy but be warned.
In 2017, the Cambridge District
had one of the highest rates of
bike theft in England and Wales
so lock it up. In the centre of
Cambridge is one of the world's
most well known and respected
universities. Founded in twelve
hundred and 8, it's the fourth
oldest university in the world
still teaching. One of the
jewels in the university's
crown is its libraries and this
is the big one. Cambridge
University Library holds around
8 million books, manuscripts,
maps and journals and it was
thought some more salacious
material. For a long time, it
was undergraduate folk law that
the library tower held a vast
stockpile of Victorian-aged
pornography but no. This year,
the tower opened up its secrets
and revealed it was used to
store books and other items
thought to be not good enough
for the main building. This
material is now regarded as an
important resource.
One of the best ways to see
Cambridge's hidden spots is by
boat or punt to be exact.
Punting began in the early 20th
century and remains the best
way to explore the river cam
and its many bridges, 25 in
all. This is the mathematical
bridge. Despite looking curved,
it's actually made entirely of
straight timber. Safely on dry
land, it's time for a pint.
This is the eagle. It was here
in 1953 that Francis Creek
charged in interrupting lunch
time service to announce that
he and James Watson had
discovered the secret of life.
How DNA carries genetic
information. Hope someone
offered him a drink. Keeping
with Tradition just a few
meters down the road is Chop
House. This no nonsense steak
restaurant has a classic
English menu. Try the sticky
toffee pudding if you got room.
But it's not all old England.
This is Pint Shop which offers
23 tap craft beers and 100 gin
options.
There are plenty of places to
stay in the city but if you
want to get some country air,
just a short drive out of town
is Clopton Courtyard. Here you
can rent your own barn, there
are six to choose from and
enjoy the quintessentially
English countryside
surroundings. Not a bad spot to
finish off your day. You.